<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Minerals Framework</name>
  <author>Zachary S. L. Foster</author>
	<packageId>zacharyfoster.mineralsframework</packageId>
  <description>
v0.1

NOTE: Under development. This is my first time adding mods to Steam, so I have some learning to do and I am sure things will need fixing.

An overhaul of anything mineable and the foundation for the "Minerals" collection of mods. This mod does not add any content to the game, but provides a framework for other mods to build upon. Rocks and minerals produced by this framework have the following improvements over vanilla:

- More realistic and organic appearance, supporting different sizes, number of textures, distribution of texture positions, and random scattering
- More customizable mining products, including support for multiple products, product probabilities, and product quantities
- Mining products are randomly dropped while mining instead of all at once when the rock is destroyed
- Miner skill affects amount of resources mined
- Minerals have a "size" that affects how many resources can be mined from them and their appearance
- Minerals can grow, shrink, spawn, and despawn in response to environmental conditions, such as temperature, precipitation, and light levels
- An optional "snowy" texture that appears when enough snow has accumulated nearby
- A "mining speed" property makes how easy it is to mine independent of rock hit points

See other mods in the "Minerals" collection to get the full experience:

- Minerals Rock: Complete overhaul of mountains and rocks
- Minerals Sparkle: Valuable crystals that can be mined for gems in remote and extreme biomes
- Minerals Frozen: Dynamic ice and snow that can be used for building and cooling rooms

The Minerals mods are still being balanced. Feel free to let me know if anything needs to be adjusted!

I am not aware of any incompatibilities with other mods, but please let me know if you find any.
  </description>
  <url>https://github.com/zachary-foster/MineralsFramework</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>sarg.alphabiomes</li>
		<li>brrainz.harmony</li>
	</loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
